### SAVITHA PREMKUMAR

**UI DEVELOPER | 9, KEATING RISE, NORTHCROSS, AUCKLAND** 

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

#### **UI/WEB/FRONT END**

**Developer** with close to 5 years of experience in building and supporting responsive web applications, spanning domains like leasing, ecommerce and media, having focus on front-end performance optimization, delivering in the Agile methodology. I bring strong technical skills, Agile experience (Scrum master), adaptability and development experience, coupled with a passion for learning and growth.

### **SKILLS VS YEARS**

jQuery	4.8
JavaScript	4.8
CSS/CSS3	4.8
HTML/HTML5	4.8
Responsive web	
development	1
Bootstrap	1
Node.js, npm	0.5
Apache Velocity CMS a	and
Templates (VTL)	2
Agile SCRUM Master	1

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## UI DEVELOPER • OLIOGO (E-COMMERCE STARTUP), FREELANCER • JUNE 2016 – MARCH 2017

**Oliogo** is an e-commerce marketplace aiming to serve distributors and manufacturers of industrial components a platform to directly market their products.

Worked remotely for my former colleague Rahul's e-commerce startup to help him build and launch Oliogo.

Oliogo was built using WAMP (Windows, Apache, MySQL, PHP) stack, WordPress and used WooCommerce, a customizable ecommerce platform. I specifically worked as a front-end developer setting up the responsive online shop using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap and adding several features like shopping cart, checkout, blog, contact form, product sliders, product pages, etc.

# SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER • TIME ANALYTIC AND SHARED SERVICES PVT. LTD, BANGALORE, INDIA • OCTOBER 2015 – MAY 2016

**Time Inc** is the world-renowned media company, based out of New York, most famous for its Time magazine.

#### **Project / Team: SUBS3**

Senior **JavaScript** developer for Subscriptions team responsible for the creation of all Online subscription forms for **Time** and its iconic brands like **Sports Illustrated**, **Health**, **Travel + Leisure**, Food & Wine to name a few.

#### Role and Responsibilities

• Built jQuery, JavaScript and HTML-based responsive ads, touts and other holiday/special offer pages along with weekly edits compelling more clicks from users. Pushed cross-sell and up-sell opportunities with each purchase.







- Responsible for **analysis**, **development** and **deployment** of new **responsive** subscription forms for both desktops and **mobiles** for the **print** and **digital** business, adhering to the weekly hard deadlines as this is critical to the business.
- Came up with fix for security vulnerability against cross-site scripting attacks (XSS) for all existing and new microsites, thereby passing the internal security audit on time.
- Improved team productivity and bettered capacity planning by introducing JIRA process. Initiated and developed a JIRA Reports PoC application in Node.js for the same.

Technology/Frameworks: JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5,

CSS3, Node.js, **npm**, Dataframe, C3.js, Apache Velocity templates

Environment/Tools: JIRA, Sublime Text, CVS,

FileZilla, Putty, Browser debuggers

### WEB DEVELOPER • APTEAN SOFTWARE INDIA PVT. LTD, BANGALORE, INDIA • FEBRUARY 2014 – AUGUST 2015

Aptean Software, founded in 2012, and currently held by Vista Equity Partners, is an **enterprise application software** provider company with a host of CRM, ERP, SCM and KM products under its wing.

#### **Project / Team: Truition**

Truition is a customizable enterprise level **e-commerce** product with features like Inventory and Order Management, Search & Merchandising, Discount Engine, Auctions, Business Intelligence, etc. for large organizations. Truition had customers like **Dell**, Sirius XM US and Canada, **Delta Airlines**, Rogers Magazines.

#### Role and Responsibilities

- Front end **JavaScript developer** responsible for customizing the **storefronts**(UI) for various customers, adhering to **W3C standards**.
- Ran successful holiday campaigns (Black Fridays, Christmas, etc.) for customers by developing themed pages, email marketing, re-marketing products to help them achieve high sales.
- Front end performance optimization: Improved page load speed by 80% for various customers.
- Developed the quicker one page checkout process to enhance customer experience and conversion rates.
- Ensured cross-browser compatibility of the application (Firefox, IE 10 and upwards, Chrome).
- Adding Omniture and Google Analytics code snippets to storefront pages for analytics.
- Drove up customer trust by integrating PowerReviews for the Rogers Magazine website, by way of which customers can read reviews from the web and rate the magazines themselves.

Technology/Frameworks: JavaScript, jQuery 1.7.1, jQuery Colorbox, HTML, CSS, AJAX, Apache

Velocity CMS, Velocity Template Language







Chrome and IE Debuggers

#### **Project / Team: Tungsten**

Tungsten is a new loosely-coupled module-based **e-commerce** solution written in **.NET 4.5.1** to replace the existing Truition product. This was a gigantic effort involving **cross-functional teams** in Vietnam, India, Canada and Germany collaborating on building a new product in an **Agile** methodology.

#### Role and Responsibilities

- Took **ownership** for developing PayFlow **payment gateway**. Liaised with clients and PayFlow team on the **requirements** and did the **analysis** and **development** (using **OAuth**) of PayFlow and Points.com. Both were integrated as plug-in **REST APIs** with the product.
- Took up the role of **Scrum Master**, facilitated **Daily Standup** and planning sessions. Involved in scoping of **weekly sprint** activities.
- Actively trained new hires and mentored fellow team members on the existing product.

Technology/Frameworks: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, ASP.Net Web API

Environment/Tools: Visual Studio 2013, **TFS**, **Git** 

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER • SOCIÉTÉ GÉNÉRALE GLOBAL SOLUTION CENTRE PVT. LTD., BANGALORE, INDIA • AUGUST 2011 – JANUARY 2014

Société Générale, is France's third largest bank with multi-national presence in banking and financial services. I had the privilege of working with this over 150-year-old huge organization, specifically for ALD, its fleet managing and operational car leasing subsidiary company. ALD Automotive is ranked #3 worldwide and #1 in Europe by number of contracts under management.

#### Project /Team: Migration of ALDNET to ALDNet 2.0

ALDNet 2.0 (<a href="https://www.aldnet.fr/portalctnr/aldnetpal">https://www.aldnet.fr/portalctnr/aldnetpal</a>) is a web application used to manage car fleets by clients of ALD, developed using **jQuery**, **JavaScript** and Convertigo (open source enterprise mobility platform).

#### Role and Responsibilities

- Effectively developed over 70 W3C-compliant screens and widgets in this application with crossbrowser compatibility
- Implemented **PDF** and **Excel download** of reports for ALDNet 2.0
- Roles and responsibilities include analyzing the specifications, writing the unit test case document, development, **unit**, **functional** and **regression** testing.
- Single-handedly wrote screens and widgets in **jQuery**, **jqPlot**, **JavaScript** and **Flexigrid** for Customer Portal, an online platform for the drivers and fleet managers of ALD to conduct their day to day activities.







Technology/Frameworks: JavaScript, jQuery, jqPlot, Flexigrid, HTML, CSS, AJAX

Environment/Tools: Convertigo Studio, Citrix, IE Tester, Chrome and IE Debuggers

#### **Project / Team: Management Information System (MIS)**

MIS is a Java-based web application in Struts 1.0 used for making, reviewing, approving and rejecting accounting adjustments at various levels in the management hierarchy. It is a system which provides information on accounting adjustment and risk adjustment to the management.

#### Role and Responsibilities

- One of the two contributors to this project and responsibilities were: Analysis, estimation, development of enhancements and bug fixes.
- Performed unit testing of developed code.

Technology/Frameworks: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Servlets and JSP

Environment/Tools: Eclipse IDE, Maven2, Tortoise SVN, WinSCP, PuTTY

#### AWARDS AND RECOGNITION

- 1.Received **spot award** for ability to pick up quickly and contribute effectively to the ALDAVAR POC in a short period of time. The project was liked and accepted by the clients.
- 2.Spot award for contribution to ALDNET 2.0 project's success awarded when I was a Software Developer in Société Générale. This was a much-anticipated project that went live on the expected date.

#### **EDUCATION**

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING, ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS • AUGUST 2011 • BMS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, BANGALORE, INDIA

FIRST CLASS WITH DISTINCTION (75.32%)

### **HOBBIES AND CAUSES I CARE ABOUT**

CYCLING • READING • WATER CONSERVATION • CHILDREN'S EDUCATION





